Guide to the Alice Coogan Travel Journals
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Alice Coogan travel journals
1975-2003
SC1114
Coogan, Alice, -2004
4.5 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Alan Coogan, 2012.
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use.
Biographical/Historical note
For more than 40 years, Stanford Travel/Study has provided Stanford alumni, friends and family with exceptional educational travel journeys to more than 80 countries each year.
Biographical/Historical note
A member of the Class of 1965 (history), Alice Coogan was among the earliest employees in Stanford Travel/Study, leaving in the early 1990s.
Arrangement note
The materials are arranged chronologically.
Access Terms
Stanford Travel/Study.; International travel.; Journals.
Collection Contents
- Navajo and Hopi reservations, Arizona, 1975 May 17-31; 1 Notebook (Box 1)
- Grand Canyon/Hells Canyon & Snake Canyon, 1976 July 31-Aug 15, 1976 Sep 3-8; 1 Notebook (Box 1)
- River Trips: Grand Canyon/Rogue River/Green River, 1977 Jun 17-Sep 12; 1 Notebook (Box 1)
- Grand Canyon, 1978 Jun 24-Jul 9; 1 Notebook (Box 1)
- East Africa, 1978 Aug 13-Sep 4; 1 Notebook (Box 1)
- Egypt, 1979 Mar 21-Apr 9; 1 Notebook (Box 1)
- Manila, Philippines, 1979 Aug 13-Sep 2; 1 Notebook (Box 1)
- Caribbean/Mississippi, 1980 Feb 9-17; 1 Notebook (Box 1)
- France, 1980 May 21-Jun 15; 1 Notebook (Box 1)
- China, 1980 Sep 10-28; 1 Notebook (Box 1)
- South America, 1981 Mar 21-Apr 6; 1 Notebook (Box 1)
- Birds of Prey: Snake River/Mexico Butterfly Safari, 1981 Apr 26-30, 1987 Jan 24-28; 1 Notebook (Box 1)
- China, 1981 Aug 7-23; 1 Notebook (Box 1)
- South America, 1982 Mar 16-Apr 1; 1 Notebook (Box 1)
- Mediterranean Isles, 1982 Jun 14-30; 1 Notebook (Box 1)
- Personal Entries, 1982-1992; 1 Notebook (Box 1)
- Corfu/Venice/Paris, 1982 Sep 23-Oct 11; 1 Notebook (Box 1)
- Tanzania, 1983 Feb 4-23; 1 Notebook (Box 1)
- College in Italy & the Adriatic Sea, 1983 Jun 25-Jul 12; 1 Notebook (Box 1)
- Cross-Country Road Trips, 1983 Oct 24-Nov 16, 1985 Oct 28-Nov 11, 1986 Sep 8-21; 1 Notebook (Box 1)
- Oaxaca/Mexico City/Personal Entries, 1983 Apr 21-28, 1983 Dec 20-Feb 13, 1983 Jan 3-Oct 5; 1 Notebook (Box 1)
- Australia/New Zealand, 1983 Aug 30-Sep 21; 1 Notebook (Box 1)
- Seminar in France, 1984 Sep 8-25; 1 Notebook (Box 1)
- Western Mediterranean College (Spain/Italy), 1984 Apr 13-28; 1 Notebook (Box 1)
- Seminar in Spain, 1985 Mar 29-Apr 14; 1 Notebook (Box 1)
- France, 1985 Sep 16-28; 1 Notebook (Box 1)
- Valencia & Lisbon/Valencia/London, 1984 Jul 22-26, 1985 Dec 19-31; 1 Notebook (Box 1)
- India, 1986 Mar 13-Apr 4; 1 Notebook (Box 1)
- Tuscany, 1986 May 16-30; 1 Notebook (Box 1)
- South America, 1986 Oct 31-Nov 22; 1 Notebook (Box 1)
- Rhone/Saone, 1987 Jun 21-Jul 9; 1 Notebook (Box 1)
- Italy, 1987 Sep 14-25; 1 Notebook (Box 1)
- Bhutan, 1987 Oct 20-Nov 10; 1 Notebook (Box 1)
- Spice Islands/Borneo, 1988 Apr 26-May 12; 1 Notebook (Box 2)
- Rhone/Soane, 1988 Jul 17-Aug 5; 1 Notebook (Box 2)
- Asian Capitals, 1988 Nov 6-25; 1 Notebook (Box 2)
- Oaxaca, 1989 Feb 18-28; 1 Notebook (Box 2)
- Kansas/London, 1989 Jul 28-Aug 2, 1991 Nov 2-29; 1 Notebook (Box 2)
- Classical World College, 1989 Sep 21-Oct 12; 1 Notebook (Box 2)
- Suitcase Seminar in Paris, 1989 Nov 13-26; 1 Notebook (Box 2)
- Antarctica, 1990 Jan 11-26; 1 Notebook (Box 2)
- Belgium/Dutch Waterways, 1990 Apr 13-29; 1 Notebook (Box 2)
- Zimbabwe, 1990 Jun 7-18; 1 Notebook (Box 2)
- Japan, 1990 Oct 15-26; 1 Notebook (Box 2)
- Caribbean/Venezuela, 1991 Mar 19-Apr 6; 1 Notebook (Box 2)
- South Pacific College, 1991 Sep 1-19; 1 Notebook (Box 2)
- Aurora II Inspection Trip, 1992 Jan 18-23; 1 Notebook (Box 2)
- Bombay/Cairo, 1992 Apr 21-May 18; 1 Notebook (Box 2)
- Bombay/Alexandria, 1992 Apr 23-May 1; 1 Notebook (Box 2)
- Galapagos, 1992 Jun 18-Jul 1; 1 Notebook (Box 2)
- Paris/London, 1992 Nov 7-10; 1 Notebook (Box 2)
- Personal Entries, 1992 Aug 18-Dec 16, 1994 Jan 11-Oct 14; 1 Notebook (Box 2)
- South India, 1992 Sep 12-24; 1 Notebook (Box 2)
- Christmas Vacations: Minneapolis/Dallas, 1991 Dec 23-30, 1992 Dec 23-30; 1 Notebook (Box 2)
- Singapore/Bombay, 1993 Mar 24-Apr 5; 1 Notebook (Box 2)
- Bahamas & Florida/Southern Road Trip/South Africa/The Keys/London, 1993 Jun-Jul 30, 1994 Dec 28-Jan 1, 1995 Oct 31-Nov 18, 1995, Apr 26-May 1, 1995 Jun 23-Jul 21; 1 Notebook (Box 2)
- Silk Road College, 1994 Apr 15- May 6; 1 Notebook (Box 2)
- Southern Africa/Sikkim, 1993 Aug 17-31, 1993 Oct 17-Nov 8; 1 Notebook (Box 2)
- France/London & Paris, 1989 Jun 8-21, 1994 Aug 16-21; 1 Notebook (Box 2)
- Beijing-Moscow/Berlin, 1994 Oct 11-19, 1995 May 15-24; 1 Notebook (Box 2)
- Solomon Islands/Grenadines/Fiji (sketches), 1991 Sep 8-1992 Jan 21; 1 Notebook (Box 3)
- Travel Sketches (various locations, includes landscapes, portraits, still lifes), 1991 Nov 24-1999 Jun 2; 1 Notebook (Box 3)
- Yangtze/Beijing, 1995 Sep 11-27, 1996 Sep 11-25; 1 Notebook (Box 3)
- London/South Africa, 1995 Jul 13-21, 1996 Jan 14-Feb 14; 1 Notebook (Box 3)
- Sweden, 1996 Jul 30-Aug 16; 1 Notebook (Box 3)
- Brazil, 1995 Nov 16-Dec 6; 1 Notebook (Box 3)
- Canada, 1997 Aug 25-Sep 2; 1 Notebook (Box 3)
- The Marsh, 1996 June 10-2000 Oct 26; 1 Notebook (Box 3)
- South Africa, 1997 Feb 8-Apr 28; 1 Notebook (Box 3)
- Personal Entries, 1997 May 19-2000 Aug 27; 1 Notebook (Box 3)
- Cape Town/Nairobi, 1997 Nov 11-1998 Feb 21; 1 Notebook (Box 3)
- French Rivers College/Japan/Royal Courts of Northern Italy, 1998 Jun 23-Jul 6, 1998 Aug 18-26, 1998 Sep 9-19; 1 Notebook (Box 3)
- Personal Entries, 1998; 1 Notebook (Box 3)
- Hong Kong/Cambodia/Jaipur/Uzbekistan/London, 1999 Feb 4-26, 1999 Mar 2-6; 1 Notebook (Box 3)
- Travel Sketches (various locations, includes landscapes, portraits, still lifes), 1999 Oct 30-2002 Jan 3; 1 Notebook (Box 3)
- Tuscany/Peru, 1999 Jun 18-July 4, 1999 Aug 17-31; 1 Notebook (Box 3)
- Lisbon, 1999 Oct 26-27; 1 Notebook (Box 3)
- Personal Entries, 2000; 1 Notebook (Box 3)
- Galapagos/Rainforest Expedition, 1992 June 16-Jul 1; 1 Notebook (Box 3)
- Yangtze/Beijing, 2000 Sep 21-Oct 10; 1 Notebook (Box 3)
- Scotland (sketches)/Italian Renaissance College, 2001 Aug 31-Sep 12; 1 Notebook (Box 3)
- Personal Entries (various travel locations), 2001; 1 Notebook (Box 3)
- Personal Entries, 2002; 1 Notebook (Box 3)
- Personal Entries, 2003 Jan 1-Oct 9; 1 Notebook (Box 3)
- North Carolina (includes sketches)/British Columbia & Alaska, 2003 Mar 13-Apr 10, 2003 May 22-Jun 9; 1 Notebook (Box 3)